[ Watch on kissFlix.co ]
[Abyss]
[2001]
[Huangshui Technical School]
Hello, I'm calling to report an accident.
I accidentally hit someone while driving.
[Episode 8]
The 15th?
The 15th of this month...
How can I remember something
from that long ago?
It only rained
on those few days this month.
It was a rainy day?
Now that you mention it,
it does ring a bell.
I wasn't planning to go out that day,
but then I realized we were out of rice,
so I went to buy some.
I actually ran into Han on my way back.
This clock is malfunctioning?
It's mechanical
and hasn't been wound for ages.
This calendar is from over 10 years ago.
Why do you still keep it?
I just never got around to changing it.
I rarely come back here
after my parents passed away.
What illness did your father die from?
Liver cancer.
You said you rarely come back,
but the room's kept pretty clean.
An unoccupied house
stays nice
with just an occasional cleaning.
Humans are
actually the dirtiest in this world.
The customers at your internet cafe
all say you are
a generous, straightforward,
and reasonable guy.
How could you have
such an extreme way of thinking?
Which one is the real you?
They are both real me.
Don't you feel it's contradictory?
Humans are a mass of contradictions
in and of themselves.
Is it illegal for me to think this way?
SN!
Bro!
What made you think of
treating me to a meal?
I want to verify something with you.
I hope I'm not holding up your work.
No, not at all.
I quit my job.
You quit?
When?
Just today,
right at this moment.
Does Zhang Chengguo know this?
I didn't tell anyone.
I just grabbed my things
and left right away.
I unilaterally got rid of them.
Wait.
You were doing just fine.
Why did you quit all of a sudden?
I've always wanted
to run an internet cafe, right?
There's finally someone willing to invest.
What's that saying again?
"A true dragon isn't meant for a pond."
I, Sun Qiang, won't be stuck
in a mud pond for life.
Who's the investor?
This is a trade secret.
Trade secret, you know?
Make sure to come
and support me when it opens.
Waiter!
We want to order!
We've been sitting here for ages!
Why didn't you bring us the menu?
Tell me
about your discoveries.
He did it.
Hu Xiaofei,
Song Laifu,
and Bi Dehua—
he killed at least one of them.
He definitely knows what happened.
His good friend died, and he didn't even
want to ask more about it.
He didn't even bother hiding his emotions.
He didn't take us seriously at all.
Strategically, he looked down on us.
But tactically,
he didn't let his guard down at all.
Bi Dehua died too long ago,
so let's not mention him.
Not even a single hair
of Han Pinmu was found
at the scenes
where Hu Xiaofei and Song Laifu died.
There are no clues
at his home or the internet cafe.
I guess
the half photo you mentioned
has also been disposed of.
That makes his motive
for the murder pretty unclear.
Unless you can establish
a link between Han Pinmu
and the 3/12 Case,
you can't
even prove that he knows Mr. San.
Should we take him back for interrogation?
You are the captain. It's your call.
Save it!
If you really respect me this much,
why would you call me "Fan the Speedster"?
Tell me, what do you think?
I did see someone
come to pick a fight with Song.
But it wasn't Chen Chunli's nephew.
It was someone we both know.
Han Pinmu?
Why did Han Pinmu have a fight with Song?
I don't know.
I only caught a few words.
Han yelled that even if he had to die,
he would drag Song Laifu down with him.
That was no small argument.
Then why did Zhang Chengguo say
it was Chen Chunli's nephew?
I just made it up to fool him.
I didn't want to explain to him
my relationship with Han.
However,
I did see Han Pinmu
come to the hotel looking for Chen Chunli.
The two of them seemed quite close.
Han Pinmu and Chen Chunli are close?
Do you know Chen Chunli's son?
Nope.
Did you see anyone else
come to see Chen Chunli at the hotel
who is about Han Pinmu's age?
Besides Han Pinmu,
there was only that drunk old man.
He doesn't count, does he?
No.
Then why didn't you
tell the police when they
made inquiries at the hotel?
I'm just a security guard.
The less trouble, the better.
Besides, Han
is my acquaintance.
So I couldn't stab him in the back.
And now you can?
He betrayed me first.
Cheng,
not until recently did I find out
that he's been badmouthing me a lot.
Why?
There are over 100,000 people
in our county.
How much business
could my internet cafe take away from him?
Can you take responsibility
for what you said?
Take responsibility? How?
Go to the public security bureau
and make a statement.
Why not?
Let's go
after we finish eating.
Okay.
You're not allowed
to leave Huangshui County for a month.
For emergencies like attending funerals
or having medical treatments
that require you to leave the county,
you must get approval
from our public security bureau.
If there's anything else
you need to inquire about,
I can go back with you right now.
No rush.
There will definitely be a chance.
Don't worry about that.
Just wait in the internet cafe
and play a few more games,
in case you can't play anymore.
That would be a pity.
Right?
Hello.
Got it.
[Police]
See?
Plans can't keep up with changes.
You really have to come
to the bureau with me for a proper talk.
You know
why we brought you back here, right?
I don't know.
Alright then.
Take a look. Do you know this person?
Nope.
Is he a customer at my internet cafe?
Stop playing dumb.
You two have known each other
for a long time,
and you have a deep-rooted conflict.
I don't even know his name.
He's the parking lot attendant
at Huangzhiyuan Hotel.
He calls himself Song Laifu.
Some people also call him Mr. San.
So he's that Song Laifu
you were talking about.
Han Pinmu,
stop pretending.
Someone saw you two arguing,
and you even threatened to kill him.
How do you explain that?
It's pretty easy to explain.
For example, I went to have a meal
at Huangzhiyuan Hotel,
and he was
the parking lot attendant there.
We got into an argument
over the parking fee,
but I don't quite remember now.
You threatened to kill him
just because of a parking fee?
Do you think we'd believe that?
I was young and cocky,
bragging without watching my mouth.
Is that illegal?
Han Pinmu,
don't think you're really smart.
We know your situation very well.
-Letting you...
-Letting me come clean
is to give me a chance
for a lighter sentence
by helping with the case.
I understand.
Officers,
these tricks
might work on someone
who's got something to hide.
But I've got nothing to feel guilty about.
You can't scare me.
Why have you never been curious
about what happened to Song Laifu?
It has nothing to do with me.
When I was little, my dad just taught me
that unnecessary curiosity
can get you killed.
Even though he's a jerk,
he was right about that.
Since you brought up your dad,
let's talk about him for a bit.
In 2001, your biological mother
had a car accident.
Two months later,
your dad married your stepmother, Du Juan.
Pretty efficient, huh?
Could it be that
your dad had been cheating all along?
I just came up with another explanation.
Maybe
the person who said
I argued with Song Laifu
was lying.
Is he a security guard
at Huangzhiyuan Hotel?
I just remembered someone
I have a grudge against.
I don't want to talk about that right now.
I just want to talk about your parents.
What do my parents have to do
with Song Laifu?
Your dad had an affair with Du Juan,
and your mom happened to die
in a car accident.
So your dad married his mistress.
You couldn't accept it,
so your conflict with Du Juan deepened.
Let me make this clear to you.
It wasn't a coincidence.
The drunk driver who killed my mom
was hired by Du Juan.
Du Juan got my mom killed.
She was the real murderer.
I went to the public security bureau
and the traffic police office,
but no one believed me.
You useless cops
deserve to die just like Du Juan.
The police investigated it.
There was no evidence to prove
the contract killing you mentioned.
That was
just because you were incompetent.
So you had Hu Xiaofei
find the desperado, Mr. San,
and asked him to kill Du Juan.
No, I didn't.
That was a real coincidence.
No, it was karma
getting her.
How do you know Chen Chunli?
Who?
Chen Chunli.
You once went to the hotel
to look for her.
My dad investigated the 3/12 Case
for Du Juan back then.
He found out about Chen Chunli
through many channels.
I went to find her with my dad.
To ask about some details of the case,
my dad even paid Chen Chunli.
You're lying.
Since you hate Du Juan so much,
how could you possibly
go track down the suspect with your dad?
You can ask Chen Chunli
if you don't believe me.
I wanted to talk about this,
but you just interrupted me abruptly.
Who can prove
that I argued with Song Laifu?
Sun Qiang?
We can't answer this question for now.
It must be him.
I know he works as a security guard
at that hotel.
You know what?
Sun Qiang also wants to open
an internet cafe.
He's always seen me as his competitor
and had delusions
that I would stop or persecute him.
But I actually couldn't care less
about what he wants to do.
He was very likely lying to frame me.
Could you ask him to provide
the video of me arguing with Song Laifu?
Does he have it?
You can't just
take his word for it, right?
Even if...
Even if I did argue with Song Laifu,
so what?
What does that prove?
The law is about
the presumption of innocence.
You need evidence to prove what I did,
and I don't need to prove
what I didn't do.
[Public Security]
This man is well prepared.
He must have
anticipated all sorts of situations.
He had an extraordinarily strong reaction
when we
talked about his parents just now.
If Du Juan really hired someone
to murder his mother,
then his motive for the crime back then
makes perfect sense.
You're stating the obvious.
As long as he thinks so,
the motive just makes sense.
But what's the use
if you have no evidence?
The fact that he dared to say it himself
means he's sure we don't have evidence.
A confession alone
is not enough to close this case.
The point is that
we don't even have a confession now.
[Huangshui Public Security]
Li Cheng once saw that half of the photo.
But he didn't find it.
I know he didn't find it.
I mean,
can you make a breakthrough
from this angle?
He's got
strong psychological defenses, huh?
Push him again from this angle,
just like you did
when you found the angle with his parents.
And his relationship
with Hu Xiaofei and Bi Dehua is definitely
not as simple as he claimed.
No, no way.
Only a few people can enter his room.
If the photo you mentioned doesn't work,
Li Cheng
might be exposed.
Now you're getting anxious?
Where were you before?
You could just write a report openly
and let Hu Sen and Wang Tao go!
That's it!
Now you're worrying for nothing.
You know nothing.
[Huangshui Public Security]
The county is not so big.
And the internet cafe's got
all kinds of people coming and going.
It's inevitable that someone
would know
that Hu and the others are cops.
We have to use newbies, new faces,
you know?
Besides,
are they anywhere near Li Cheng's level
in gaming?
They couldn't even play together!
Fine, fine. You know everything.
You know it all.
Since you know it all,
get him to confess in 24 hours.
Stop acting like a great detective.
Without a confession,
we'll have no choice but to let him go.
Come on.
Hurry, here, right here.
Rub this, rub this.
Captain Fan, Master.
Li Cheng.
You know Han Pinmu
and Sun Qiang better than we do.
Do you think
Sun Qiang's testimony is credible?
I think it is credible.
But on our way here,
he said he was the only one
who saw Han Pinmu
and Song Laifu having a fight.
Zhang Chengguo also heard it from him.
There is no one else to corroborate it.
Han Pinmu claimed that
Sun Qiang has a conflict with him.
Is that true?
Yep.
[Night of Champions]
[Get a pentakill
and earn ¥20 in free play time!]
[Benteng Internet Cafe]
Can I participate in the interrogation?
No way.
What's the point of your participation?
I always feel that
Han Pinmu let me see
that photo on purpose.
For what purpose?
The other half of the photo
was found at Hu Xiaofei's death scene.
If such a coincidence
was intentionally designed,
wouldn't he be
bringing trouble on himself?
What if Han Pinmu intentionally
exposed himself
to cover for the real murderer?
Who is he covering for?
His family is all dead.
You guys at the internet cafe
are his best friends.
Who is he covering for?
Take a bold guess.
Could it be Chen Chunli
taking revenge after all these years?
That's impossible.
Zhao, if we guess like this,
we're going off track.
No way, this is impossible.
You already know Song Laifu
is a fake identity, right?
Big Red Date told me.
Zhao.
The fake Song Laifu is nicknamed Mr. San.
We want to figure out
why he stayed in Huangshui.
But we've run into a lot of resistance
in investigating Li Zhengbin.
He's got a super busy business
as well as complex social connections.
We haven't
found anything suspicious for now.
Zhao, I can't believe it.
You literally tell him everything.
At this point,
you still don't see Li Cheng as one of us?
But since you're in this uniform,
you can't be lax
about necessary procedures.
If we can't get anything
on Han Pinmu this time,
Li Cheng will have to keep
staying undercover by his side
and monitoring his movements!
We can't give him a chance
to escape or commit another crime!
Captain Fan,
can you think of a way
to turn Li Cheng's work
into an official mission?
As omnipotent as you are,
you can pull it off with just a report.
I can consider it.
But when he transfers
to the Criminal Investigation Brigade
one day, he should follow me, not you.
Deal?
Deal! I mean, why not?
Li Cheng.
Come on, change the way you address him.
Master Fan, I'll follow you from now on.
Oh, look at this.
Look at the shameless master
and apprentice.
The apprentice takes after his master.
Captain Fan, Captain Zhao,
something happened
at Han Pinmu's internet cafe.
[Benteng Internet Cafe]
Did you see the arsonist?
No, the arsonist already ran away
when I came out.
Where is your boss?
He was taken away by you.
Taken away by us? What do you mean?
The police took him away.
You were the first
to notice the fire, right?
I smelled smoke,
so I ran out from inside.
I saw the fire
and hurried back to get the extinguisher.
Wei,
what happened?
I don't know.
Someone set a fire
and burned the storefront.
It's you.
Hello, officer.
You...
Zhang.
Someone saw the arsonist
running that way.
Let's check
the surveillance footage nearby.
Got it.
You know this policeman?
Someone once made trouble
at my mom's workplace,
and he helped handle it.
Didn't expect him to still remember me.
Can you still open for business?
We'll be closed for at least half a month.
Good thing no customers were injured.
Otherwise, we wouldn't even
pass the fire inspection
and would surely be shut down.
I think that's the arsonist's purpose—
to burn down our shop.
I'm wondering when the Boss will be back.
How am I supposed to explain this to him?
[Benteng Internet Cafe]
[Public Security]
-Captain Zhao.
You didn't take a nap?
Why sleep so much in life,
when you'll sleep forever after death?
I sprained my back again.
Then you're the one
who should get more rest.
You actually care about people?
I have some news for you.
Your internet cafe was burned down.
Who did it?
We're still investigating.
People always say "murder and arson."
If arson is mentioned
in the same breath as murder,
the charge must be quite serious, huh?
See?
He's not surprised at all.
I'm running a business.
It's inevitable to offend
some crazy, silly men
who never think about the consequences.
Fine.
Then I'll tell you one more thing.
Let's see
if we can surprise him this time.
Your friend, Hu Xiaofei,
is one of the suspects in the 3/12 Case.
That means your stepmother, Du Juan,
was very likely killed by Hu Xiaofei
and Bi Dehua.
Xiaofei was also involved?
See?
He's still not surprised.
I had my suspicions after reading
Xiaofei's novel, "Abyss."
A lot of stuff in the novel
matches what my dad painstakingly
dug into back then.
But I never told him those details.
What details did you
and your dad find out?
Just what you already know—
the 3 possible suspects,
the time and locations of the 5 cases,
the victims' gender, age, identity,
and some family backgrounds.
The reports back then were pretty vague
on these details,
while Xiaofei wrote them
pretty accurately.
Hu Xiaofei's novel wasn't finished.
Did he ever tell you
how the rest of the story would unfold?
Nope.
The novel didn't get many views,
so he wrote more and more slowly.
Did Hu Xiaofei write the novel
really just to make money?
What else could it be?
For repentance?
Your friend, Hu Xiaofei,
is a suspect in the 3/12 Case,
and the person you hate is a victim in it.
It's hard to convince us
that you weren't involved.
I'll say it again—
providing evidence is your job.
Okay.
Besides you,
who else was Hu Xiaofei close to
back then?
Bi Dehua, I guess.
Didn't you claim that
you had no idea about their relationship?
I know
they often played basketball together,
but I wasn't really into basketball,
so I rarely went to the court.
Back when Bi Dehua was identified
as the murderer in the 3/12 Case,
how did you feel?
I can't quite recall.
Was there anything unusual
about Hu Xiaofei's reaction
when he learned it?
I don't remember that either.
It was such a big deal,
and you don't remember anything?
Officers,
it's been 7 or 8 years.
Besides the samples
you went to great lengths
to find back then,
what else could've been preserved forever?
Memories?
They're the most unreliable, aren't they?
Take it slow.
-Be careful.
-It's okay.
Be careful.
[Benteng Internet Cafe]
I'm sorry, Boss.
I failed to keep the internet cafe safe.
It's not your fault.
I've been wanting to give everyone
a long vacation for the past few years,
but I couldn't find the chance.
Now we've got the chance, right?
I hereby announce that
Benteng Internet Cafe will be closed
for a month
for a revamp.
All employees will be on leave
with full pay.
Hooray, Boss!
Boss, Kun resigned.
He was probably poached by SN.
Everyone has their own ambitions.
Let him be.
I'm relieved to see you
in good spirits.
Since the internet cafe is closed,
I'll head back now.
Hold on.
Let's talk
over a meal.
Let's go. Take my car.
Help me hold it.
Okay.
Yu!
Come help me hold it together.
He's quite heavy.
Hold it steady.
Where are we going to eat?
There's a private restaurant
not far up ahead.
Few people know about it.
Based on what Zhang Chengguo said,
we found his friend, Wang Long.
Wang Long is a contractor,
and he confirmed that Zhang Chengguo
indeed met Mr. San while playing cards
at the construction site.
We reorganized the timeline
and found that after obtaining
Song Laifu's identity, this Mr. San
first worked at Wang Long's
construction site for 3 months.
Then he utilized the negligence
of the household registration personnel
to get a new second-generation ID card.
Only after getting
a squeaky-clean identity
was he arranged by Zhang Chengguo
to work as a security guard at the hotel.
Zhang Chengguo can't be
cleared of suspicion for now.
Let's focus
on Li Zhengbin for now.
Li Zhengbin is rich and powerful.
The probability of him participating
in the robbery and rape is lower, right?
I didn't say
he was the direct perpetrator,
but to some extent,
he might have provided help.
What if Zhang Chengguo is
Mr. San's accomplice?
Like, Mr. San worked
at Wang Long's construction site
just to normally meet Zhang Chengguo?
That would require considering
the issue of identity exposure
from a long time ago.
But once the crimes
Mr. San committed were exposed...
[Sender: Elite Student]
A friend is treating me to dinner.
I won't be home for dinner.
Is it necessary to go to such lengths
for an accomplice?
I'm going out for a bit.
Where are you going? We're in a meeting.
There's an emergency at home.
I'll check the meeting minutes
when I get back.
What's up?
It was my mom calling.
She was probably waiting for me
to have dinner at home.
I suddenly told her
I wasn't going back for dinner,
so she called to ask.
Just ignore her.
Then ask her to come along.
I haven't met your mom yet.
Why ask her to come?
Didn't you want to chat with me?
It would be awkward with her around.
What are you doing?
[Old Foodie] [A friend is treating me
to dinner. I won't be home for dinner.]
Focus on driving!
You saved your mom's contact
as "Old Foodie"?
My mom has a huge appetite.
She can eat 3 bowls of rice
in a single meal.
I'm sending her the address.
You can add a few words.
She can come if she wants to,
and it's fine if she doesn't.
I just need to show
my manners as your friend.
[Old Foodie] [No. 8, Wolong Yinquan Villa]
[Inbox] [Old Foodie]
No. 8, Wolong Yinquan Villa.
[Sender: Elite Student]
Mom, my friend just sent
the restaurant address.
He said he wanted to invite you
to join us for dinner.
He's just being polite.
Don't take it seriously.
[Public Security]
No. 8.
Is this a place to eat?
Mr. Han!
You haven't come for a long time.
Are there any private rooms upstairs?
Yes, this way, please.
Please mind the steps.
How many of you today?
Two.
Okay.
Be careful.
This way, please.
This place looks unusually posh.
Han, you're really broadening my horizons.
I rarely come here either.
You're being too modest.
The waiters here all know you.
I'm just a nobody.
I'm actually feeling out of place
staying somewhere this high-end.
What do you want to talk about?
I just need someone to open up to.
I'll just say whatever comes to mind.
Then why don't you
talk to Wei and the others?
They are not like you.
There are a lot of things
they can't understand,
but you can.
Am I that special?
This restaurant doesn't have a menu.
No matter how many guests are
in a private room,
the dishes served are the same.
I just forgot to ask
about the main course today.
This sounds even more luxurious.
It's definitely not a place I can afford.
I only knew
there was such a place in Huangshui
because I came here with my dad
when I was little.
What does your dad do?
He was a driver.
A driver?
My dad and the boss here
used to be colleagues.
My dad was the driver,
and the boss here was
the executive assistant.
Later, the company went bankrupt.
The executive assistant
started his own business.
He opened restaurants and hotels
and got into real estate
as his business kept expanding,
while my dad
could only live off his savings.
He got seriously ill
and died a couple of years later.
Luckily, I pushed him to open
an internet cafe for me early on.
You have no idea.
Business licenses were
very hard to get back then.
Without his connections,
I couldn't have gotten one.
There aren't many successful big shots
in Huangshui.
In view of this assistant-turned-boss's
business empire,
could it be the boss of Huangzhiyuan,
Li Zhengbin?
Yes,
he is the boss of this restaurant.
You know him?
He's a famous boss.
I've heard of him more or less.
Your dad and Li Zhengbin were colleagues?
That's awesome!
Li Zhengbin is the awesome one.
The veterans of our county's
early infrastructure projects
came from all over the country.
When people get old,
they miss the taste of their hometowns.
So Li Zhengbin
hired chefs from these leaders' hometowns
and shipped ingredients
to serve them specifically.
Later, he built
even stronger connections
than when he was an executive assistant.
Did you notice it just now?
This restaurant doesn't have a sign.
But it's always had a name—
Homesickness.
An old leader gave it this name,
meaning the enduring homesickness
and longing to return to one's roots.
Everything here
was carefully selected by Li Zhengbin,
including the waitresses.
What kind of feelings
is this "Homesickness" anyway?
Funny, huh?
My stepmother was a waitress here
back then...
Du Juan.
Just a few years
after this woman hooked up with my dad,
on April 28, 2001,
my mom died in a car accident,
leaving those two free to be together.
What a coincidence it was.
How perfect it was for them.
So,
you suspect that Du Juan
got your mom killed?
What I think is not important.
The traffic police said
it was an accident,
so it can only be an accident.
Sir, everything is ready.
Shall we serve the dishes?
Serve them.
Aren't we supposed
to go to the East Market?
I think you might want to come here
rather than go home.
Hu Xiaofei was my best friend.
I really wish Xiaofei were alive,
but maybe death was
a sort of relief for him.